today I would like to provide the
American people with an update on the
White House transition and our policy
plans for the first 100 days our
transition team is working very smoothly
efficiently and effectively truly great
and talented men and women patriots
indeed are being brought in and many
will soon be a part of our government
helping us to make America great again
my agenda will be based on a simple core
principle putting America first whether
it's producing steel building cars or
curing disease I want the next
generation of production and innovation
to happen right here on our great
homeland America creating wealth and
jobs for American workers as part of
this plan I've asked my transition team
to develop a list of executive actions
we can take on day one to restore a laws
and bring back our jobs it's about time
these include the following on trade I'm
going to issue our notification of
intent to withdraw from the
trans-pacific partnership a potential
disaster for our country instead we will
negotiate fair bilateral trade deals
that bring jobs and industry back onto
American shores on energy I will cancel
job-killing restrictions on the
production of American energy including
shale energy and clean coal creating
many millions of high-paying jobs that's
what we want that's what we've been
waiting for on regulation I will
formulate a rule which says that for
every one new regulation too old
regulations must be eliminated so
important or national security I will
ask the Department of Defense and the
chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to
develop a comprehensive plan to protect
America's vital infrastructure from
cyber attacks and all other form of
attacks on immigration I will direct the
Department of Labor to investigate all
abuses of visa programs that undercut
the American worker on ethics reform as
part of our plan to drain the swamp
we will impose a five-year ban on
executive officials becoming Lobby
is after they leave the administration
and a lifetime ban on executive
officials lobbying on behalf of a
foreign government these are just a few
of the steps we will take to reform
Washington and rebuild our middle class
I will provide more updates in the
coming days as we work together to make
America great again for everyone and I
mean everyone